well the entire real estate space in
India financials remember a company that
we are talking about is a company that
is one of India's largest real estate
developers both in terms of the kind of
sales volume as well as the sales actual
sales figures the company we're talking
about is macrotech developers Earth Tri
known as Loa developers the company
remember came out with this IPO between
April 7th to April 9 and the company
raised close to 2500 crores via the IPO
the IPO did see a healthy subscription
1.36 times is how the IPO was actually
over subscribed as far as the IPO Market
was concerned uh remember the base price
of the IPO was close to 486 rupees a
share and when you are talking about Loa
or macrotech developers as the company
has renamed itself as this particular
company is a residential real estate
developer with main focus as far as
afford as well as mid-income housing is
concerned given the fact that the
company has been around for such a long
time the company has presented across
most of the verticals but when you're
talking about the key Market regions the
Mumbai Metropolitan region as well as
the Pune region is when or is where the
company has majority of his projects
based in now what is it that the company
is mainly looking to do or mainly
looking to achieve via the IPO the
company is looking to reduce debt the
company has debt to close to 18,700 cror
on its books and the company would be
looking to reduce it substantially as
per the Prospectors of the IPO now
remember not only that the company when
you're comparing it to its FS has a
significantly higher net debt to equity
ratio 4.5 times net debt to equity ratio
which would be substantially coming down
post the IPO proceeds that would be
utilized so it's a significant
development as far as the company is
concerned and also as far as the sector
is concerned now when you're talking
about um the company's projects the
company also has a minor presence as far
as the London Market is concerned where
the company had fored into that
particular Market in 2013 the company
however abandoned plans of significant
expansion there and the company is
looking to sell down the assets there
and shut down its operations as far as
Lon is concern and focus on its India
operations um when you're talking about
the portfolio of the company 91
completed projects is what the company
has almost a little over 77 million
square ft is the total area that the
company has uh under development now
when you're talking about the valuations
and that is a key part that investors
look at very closely net debt of four
time four times as far as the fi20 is
concerned p0.5 to 2.5 times the company
is planning to use majority of the
proceeds almost close to 60% of the IPO
funds to reduce thatt the remainder of
the portion of the IPO would be used for
further development as well as capex
talking about the price to earnings
ratio the company at the upper end of
the price right